Finding Aid for the Poster Collection LSC.0095
UCLA Library Special Collections
- World War II--U.S. (47), Netherlands? (3), France (26)., 76 items. (Box 19)
  - Ours...to fight for / Freedom from fear. Washington, D.C.: Office of War Information, 1943 (Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office)., 1 print: color; 71 x 51 cm. (Box 19)
    Signed in lower left of image: "NORMAN ROCKWELL." Image caption: "Painting from the Saturday Evening Post." At bottom: "OWI Poster No.46 / 1943--O-511887." One of four images interpreting the four freedoms enumerated in FDR's Jan. 1941 congressional address and outlined in the Atlantic Charter issued by FDR and Churchill in Aug. 1941. Artist used his Vermont neighbors as models (Bird and Rubenstein, 37).
  - Ours...to fight for / Freedom from want. Washington, D.C.: Office of War Information, 1943 (Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office)., 1 print: color; 71 x 51 cm. (Box 19)
    Signed in lower left of image: "Norman Rockwell." Image caption: "Painting from the Saturday Evening Post." At bottom: "OWI Poster No.45 / 1943--O-511886." One of four images interpreting the four freedoms enumerated in FDR's Jan. 1941 congressional address and outlined in the Atlantic Charter issued by FDR and Churchill in Aug. 1941. Artist used his Vermont neighbors as models (Bird and Rubenstein, 37).
  - Save freedom of speech / Buy War Bonds. Washington, D.C.: Office of War Information, 1943 (Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office)., 1 print: color; 71 x 51 cm. (Box 19)
    Signed in upper right of image: "NORMAN ROCKWELL." Image caption: "Painting from the Saturday Evening Post." At bottom: "OWI Poster No.44 / 1943--O-510257." One of four images interpreting the four freedoms enumerated in FDR's Jan. 1941 congressional address and outlined in the Atlantic Charter issued by FDR and Churchill in Aug. 1941. Artist used his Vermont neighbors as models (Bird and Rubenstein, 37).
  - Save freedom of worship / Buy War Bonds. Washington, D.C.: Office of War Information, 1943 (Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office)., 1 print: color; 71 x 51 cm. (Box 19)
    Signed in lower left of image: "NORMAN ROCKWELL." Text in image: "Each according to the dictates of his own conscience." Image caption: " Painting from the Saturday Evening Post." At bottom: "OWI Poster No.43." One of four images interpreting the four freedoms enumerated in FDR's Jan. 1941 congressional address and outlined in the Atlantic Charter issued by FDR and Churchill in Aug. 1941. Artist used his Vermont neighbors as models (Bird and Rubenstein, 37).
  - Save your cans / Help pass the ammunition. [Washington, D.C.?]: War Production Board Salvage Division, [194-]., 1 print: color; 85 x 63 cm. (Box 19)
    Signed in middle left: "McCLELLAND BARCLAY USNR." Under image: four- step instructions on how to prepare tin cans for war. At lower left: War Production Board emblem.
  - Their sacrifices have saved our soil and our sons! Now let us help them...Give once for all. [S.l.]: United Nations War Relief; U.S. State Department Los Angeles area war chest, 1943 ([Union printer's mark])., 1 print: black on front, red and blue on verso; 46 x 61 cm. (Box 19)
    Fundraising brochure that folds out into poster. Verso (front and back covers when poster is folded) has more imagery, information, and instructions about the fund. Signed under drawing: "SHOEMAKER." Poster image caption: "Courtesy of Chicago Daily News."
  - Unidos para la victoria. Washington, D.C.: Coordinador de Asuntos Interamericanos, [194-]., 1 print: color; 51 x 36 cm. (Box 19)
    American poster printed for display in South America.
  - United / The United Nations fight for freedom. Washington, D.C.: Office of War Information, 1943 ([Washington, D.C.]: U.S. Government Printing Office)., 1 print: color; 71 x 51 cm. (Box 19)
    At lower left of image: "LESLIE RAGAN." At bottom: "OWI Poster No.79 / 1943--O-534058."
  - United we win. Washington, D.C.: War Manpower Commission; Office of War Information, 1943 ([Washington D.C.]: U.S. Government Printing Office)., 1 print: color; 71 x 56 cm. (Box 19)
    At lower left: "OWI photo by LIBERMAN." At bottom: "OWI Poster No.38 / 1943--O-506015."
- World War II--U.S., 15 items. (Box 40)
  (Folders 40-48 are primarily copies of Newsmap, a weekly poster prepared by the Army Information Branch, Armed Service Forces)
- World War II poster reprint, We can do it., 1 item. Poster measures 20 wide × 28 high. (Box 72)
  Reproduction of World War II poster published by the War production co-ordinating committee showing Rosie the Riveter. National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.
- World War II--Germany., 2 items. (Box 10)
  (Subject entry for World War II)
- Yedosheem! Remembrance Day..., 1971.; 1 item. (Box 72)